Jason A. Moore

2736 Emerald Mist Way, Fort Wayne, In, 46818 (260) 437-4919

Summary

Operations Professional with excellent communication skills and the ability to work crossfunctionally between multiple departments. Will bring a customer focused attitude to work every day and want to make a difference in the success of a company. With over 20 years of operations and business experience, have developed a strong ability to lead and motivate others to be successful and work as a team.

Skills

- Strategic Planning
- Project Management
- JIRA/Confluence User
- Process Automation
- HTML/CSS
- Microsoft Excel/Word/PPT
- Network Infrastructure
- GIT
- Ethernet

Accomplishments

Circuit Ticket Automation - Automated the dispatch ticket creation process of circuits by establishing rules around reading the Circuit Layout Record and determining the required techs offices. This automation eliminated the need of 8 FTE and saved the company \$330,000 of time and labor costs annually.

Equipment Provisioning Automation – Developed a method to identify network equipment that needed provisioning on a Circuit Layout Record so that only orders that needed provisioning were reviewed and auto completed all other orders. This automation eliminated the need of 9 FTE and saved the company \$375,000 of time and labor costs annually.

Education

Mount Vernon Nazarene University Mansfield, OH

• Bachelor of Science: Business Management

Experience

Frontier Communications - 7/2000 - Current

Manager – Field Operations 11/2019 – Current

- Support Field Operations daily by trouble shooting automated processes
- Review and purchase capital tools
- Cultivated processes to improve production proficiency for multiple departments.
- Deliver statistical data and give recommendations for efficiency to Senior Leadership
- Lead and manage IT and operations projects
- Performed Technical Lab testing and delivered results to Senior Leadership

Sr. Technical Analyst – Network Operations 2/2017 – 11/2019

- Support Network Operations daily by trouble shooting automated processes
- Manage Network and IT Projects end-to-end
- Sharepoint Design and development
- Developed automation for provisioning and dispatch activities
- Cultivated processes to improve production proficiency for multiple departments
- Deliver statistical data and give recommendations for efficiency to Senior Leadership
- Established and delivered on-site technical training for employees
- Performed Technical Lab testing and delivered results to Senior Leadership
- Program and analyze Ethernet Device configurations (RAD, Canoga, Ciena)

Provisioning Supervisor – Network Operations 12/2013 - 2/2017

- Managed a group of 30 technicians that completed network provisioning for the entire Frontier network
- Implemented new technology practices from vendors that included ADTRAN, Coriant, Fujitsu
- Developed and trained SS7 and 911 provisioning practices that included the proper redline provisioning commands and usage
- Provided technical support to the field for Calix, ADTRAN, RAD, Ciena Z33 and Z77, and Actelis
- Exceeded yearly goal of 85% New Order interval met
- Developed and delivered technical training for technicians

Switching Engineer – Network Operations

9/2011 - 12/2013

- Provisioned daily switch orders primary focus was on 911 Selective Routers
- Organized and implemented E911 projects
- Provided technical assistance to field technicians with trouble shooting and issue resolution
- Developed efficient processes that our team to lower the order interval and deliver the product sooner to the customer

Technical Supervisor – Network Operations

10/2007 - 9/2011

- Managed the daily operations for 65 offices and 7 technician Reporting Centers
- Led a team of 22 Central Office Technicians that provided technical resolution to customer outages
- Maintained a 90% commitment met customer service level
- Provided technical support with trouble shooting and resolving customer and network outages including SS7 and 911
- Configured and provisioned ADTRAN, Fujitsu, and Coriant devices
- Experience with managing Construction, OSP, and BTL technicians
- Managed capital budget and purchased tools

Dispatch Supervisor – Network Operations

7/2006 - 10/2007

- Led a team of 10 field dispatch associates
- Established and facilitated service outage bridges
- Performed trouble shooting for field technicians working outages
- Developed and delivered technical training to associates to improve their technical knowledge
- Provided daily customer service level results to Senior Management

Project Manager – Network Engineering

8/2004 - 7/2006

- Completed projects that involved diversifying the SS7 and E911 network
- Controlled maintenance change activity to ensure successful completion
- Performed technical trouble shooting for digital and bandwidth circuits
- Provided cost savings and overall project results to Senior leadership